Filomeno Giovetti Coelho da Silva

Healthcare Scientist | Web developer | Analyst Programmer

About me Publications

Profile

I possess a wealth of expertise encompassing laboratory practices, diagnostic troubleshooting, and a steadfast commitment to customer service excellence spanning across an array of industries.

I assumed a pivotal role in overseeing aspects of the implementation of the AFIS forensic service at the Angolan police force extending my professional experience to international horizons. Adapting to challenging and high-pressure business environments, I have adeptly steered change initiatives, ushering in modern management practices that encompass personnel, IT, and customer-supplier relations.

My technical prowess includes proficient handling of high-caliber lab equipment, clinical analyzers such as VIDAS, PANTHER, DS2, MDS, ELISA, AKTA and various molecular and gel electrophoresis platforms. I am well-versed in diagnostic software and hardware, with a comprehensive understanding of software packages like MS-DOS, OS X, Windows, MS Office, PIMS, LIMS and SQL server.

Additionally, I possess programming acumen, including Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) and skills encompassing VBA, SQL, HTML, CSS and basic Java. My understanding of LAN/WAN architecture further underscores my IT capabilities.

In summary, my extensive experience and versatile skill set make me a valuable asset with a proven track record in diverse industries and a fondness for effective management, technical prowess, and project success.

To learn more about my work history, check out <u>My Work History LinkedIn link</u>. Thanks for stopping by!

Work Experience

Locum Band 6 - Human Papilloma Virus-Unit

UK Security Health Agency - Virology Reference Department, Colindale, UK

16Nov 2020-30Jun 2023

Dealt with aspects of developing a new serological Chlamydia *Trachomatis* surveillance assay

Key Contributions:

• Purified recombinant bacterial and mammalian proteins utilising manual and AKTA methods.

• Collaborated to the Serological Chlamydia *trachomatis* Project for Surveillance assay development and validation

- Responsible for generating high-quality data for international studies (NCI,IARC).
- Developed a MS Access® database for better data mangement
- Cleaned, QA, uploaded and maintained quality and integrity of uploaded/downloaded data from database
- Operated to ISO 151589 quality standards.

Locum Band 4 - PCR-Covid19

Basildon University Hospital (NHS) - Histopathology Department, Basildon, UK

05Oct 2020-13Nov 2020

Part of the COVID19 response team.

Key Contributions:

- Performed and reported COVID19 POC testing utilising VITA PCR rapid test machine
- Received, booked, tested and reported sample results on LIMS (WinPath)
- Dealt with telephone enquiries.

Locum Band 4 - Public Health England - (PCR-Covid19)

Addenbrookes University Hospital - Microbiology Department - Cambridge - UK

20Jan 2020-01Oct 2020

Part of the COVID19 response team.

Key Contributions:

• Performed and reported on LIMS (EPIC) COVID19 and other Respiratory Virus utilising inhouse assays. Instruments used EasyMag, EZ1, KingFisher for sample extraction, QIAGEN liquid Handlers, Rotorgenes and Panther for in-house PCR and TMA assays respectively.

DBA Admin - Police Force Forensic Services (MININT)

Laboratório Central de Criminalística (LCC) - Luanda

01Ago 2017-01Jan 2020

Administrator for the National Automated Fingerprint Identification System (AFIS from IDEMIA AKA- SAFRAN Morpho)- SQL on Windows Server and run basic Oracle Database on Linux commands.

Key Contributions:

- Developed a C# solution to read and print XML information files and present them in a user-friendly format for the Police Force Forensic Lab.
- Designed and Implemented new form for the collection of fingerprint and palm prints nationally to be used with the new system.
- Reported weekly productivity for every police station enrolled in the system to Management.
- Responsible for enduring that uploading and downloading directories of the system were kept up to date.
- Managed a team of 10 people

Toxicology Analyst - Forensic Services (MININT)

Laboratório Central de Criminalística (LCC) - Luanda

07Apr 2014-31Jul 2017

Employed for Technical forensic toxicology services but, provided a business case for Pre Implementation of the Lab Accreditation Project (LMIS & LIMS) as the opportunity arose

Key Contributions:

• Performed toxicology analysis on samples utilizing GC/MS-GC/HS and LC/MS-MS instruments.

Analyst Programmer - Health Services (Intelligence Dept.)

Care Quality Commission (CQC) - Old Street, UK

11Feb 2013 - 21Mar 2014

Job summary goes here. Add as many paragraphs as you need.

Key Contributions:

- Developed, maintained, and updated programs and databases supporting the CQC's information and analysis activities.
- Improved tasks management by adding functionality to MS Access tasks manager database.
- Scripted SQL programs for data retrieval for quantitative analysis of NHS and social care data.
- Collaborated with Information Technology and statisticians to improve analytical methods.
- Contributed to quality assurance checks and continuous process improvement.
- Supported CQC's data collection, analysis, and customer service goals.

Education

Birkbeck College, University of London - London

Bachelor of Science with honors, 2004-2008

Biomedcine

Online LinkedIn training

Data Strategy, HTML, CSS - currently studying-, 2023

University of Singapore - Coursera Online

Introduction to Forensic Science, 2017

South African Police - South Africa

Morpho's Automated Fingerprint Identification System, administrator, 2017

Health Protection Agency - London

Lab Auditor, 2009

Health Protection Agency - London

Update virology, 2004

Public Health Laboratory Services - London

Basic virology, 2003

Public Health Laboratory Services - London

Basic people management, 2002

Barnet College - London

Information Technology Systems Support Technician, 2002

City & Guilds - UK

Pro & Pro Academy - London

Advanced PC Engineering, 2002

Pro & Pro advanced diploma.

Other training and CPD seminars attended in the UK

Various Clinical Pathology Accreditation (CPA) standards for medical laboratory operation and most recent UKAS seminars

© 2023 by FG Coelho da Silva | Contact

